{"tossups": [{"question": "While serving as a Senator, this man drafted the Violence Against Women Act and oversaw Robert Bork\u2019s Supreme Court confirmation hearing as chair of the Senate Judiciary Committee. This man was accused of plagiarizing a speech by Labour politician Neil Kinnock during his 1988 Presidential run. In another campaign, this man called a \u201clecture on embassy security\u201d a \u201cbunch of malarkey\u201d in a debate with 2012 Paul Ryan. For ten points, name this current Vice President of the United States.", "answer": "Joseph Robinette \u201cJoe\u201d<b> Biden</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Heinrich Kreutz names a group of these objects, whose members include Ikeya-Seki. The Giotto probe observes these objects and is named because the painter Giotto incorporated one of these objects into his <em>Adoration of the Magi</em>. The destruction of one of these objects named Shoemaker-Levy 9 was observed in 1994. Long period ones may originate from the Oort Cloud. Another of these objects last visited earth in 1986 and will return in 2061. For ten points, name these astronomical objects, one of which is named for Edmond Halley.", "answer": "<b> comet</b>s", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {}, {"question": "In 1757, tens of thousands of people who had recently performed this action died when a group led by Qa\u2019dan al-Faiz raided their caravan. Unlike a similar action, this action must be done during Dhu al-Hijjah. This action includes a series of rituals, including drinking from the Zamzam Well, the symbolic stoning of the devil, and circling the Kaaba seven times. For ten points, name this pillar of Islam that requires Muslims to, at least once in a lifetime, undertake a pilgrimage to Mecca.", "answer": "<b> Hajj</b> (prompt on pilgrimage to Mecca or similar descriptions before mentioned)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {}, {"question": "Abraham Woodhull and Robert Townsend performed this action after being recruited by Benjamin Tallmadge. While performing this action, Hercules Mulligan used his slave Cato as a courier. John Champe defected to the British army while performing this action, and while working for the British in London, Edward Bancroft performed this action. The Culper Ring was created to perform this action, whose perpetrators were considered illegal combatants. For ten points, name this wartime act for which Nathan Hale was hanged.", "answer": "<b> spying for the United States</b> (accept equivalents; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This event was foreshadowed by a poem that described rolled up tube socks and noted \u201cI\u2019m ready to let you go.\u201d A Jordan Clarkson full-court assist punctuated this event, the subject of an eBay auction of a bag of air that reached $15,000 before it was pulled. This event took place on the same day that Golden State won its 73rd game. For ten points, name this April 2016 event which featured 50 field goal attempts, 60 points, and the conclusion \u201cMamba out\u201d from a 20-year veteran of the L.A. Lakers.", "answer": "<b> Kobe Bryant\u2019s final</b> NBA<b> game</b> (or<b> Kobe Bryant\u2019s retirement</b>; accept first and/or last name; prompt on \u201cMamba out\u201d before mentioned; prompt on Lakers Season Finale)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "In this country, the Trail of the Eagles\u2019 Nests is a series of 25 castles built by this country\u2019s only king to be styled \u201cthe Great.\u201d This country\u2019s first Christian ruler, Mieszko I, conquered Mazovia for the Piast dynasty, a ruling house that ended after the death of the aforementioned Casimir the Great. For ten points, name this European country that joined in a 17th century commonwealth with Lithuania and maintained dual capitals at Vilnius and Krakow.", "answer": "<b> Poland</b> <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A reduction of the<em> pays d\u2019en haut</em> [pay den hoh] contributed to this conflict. An attack on a wagon train led to the Devil\u2019s Hole Massacre in this conflict, during which Jeffrey Amherst used smallpox infected blankets as a weapon during the siege of Fort Pitt. The battles of both Bushy and Bloody Run took place in this conflict, which opened with the siege of Fort Detroit. For ten points, name this Great Lakes-area rebellion that followed the French and Indian War, as an Ottawa chieftain tried to push the British out.", "answer": "<b> Pontiac</b>\u2019s War (or Rebellion, etc.)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Jeff Bagwell broke his hand the day before this event began. Sonia Sotomayor\u2019s injunction ended this event, which was directed by Donald Fehr. Tony Gwynn was batting .394 when this event began, costing him a chance to become the first .400 hitter since Ted Williams. Commissioner Bud Selig was heavily criticized for his actions during this event, though fans blamed both sides for their greed in negotiations. For ten points, name this 1994-95 labor stoppage that cancelled a World Series.", "answer": "1994-95<b> Major League Baseball</b> (or<b> MLB</b>)<b> strike</b> (accept 1994 and/or 1995 with the answer; do not accept references to a lockout)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "This ruler was once licked awake by a lion after an encounter with another conqueror at Taxila, which was interpreted as a sign that he would one day be king. Megasthenes visited the empire of this ruler, whose war elephants at the Battle of Ipsus led to the victory of Seleucus. This ruler\u2019s advisor Chanakya wrote the Arthashastra. This ruler\u2019s son Bindusara inherited his empire, which was founded after his defeat of the Nanda Empire. For ten points, name this ruler, the grandfather of Ashoka, who founded the Mauryan Empire.", "answer": "<b> Chandragupta</b> Maurya (accept<b> Sandrocottos</b> accept<b> Androcottus</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This initiative received aid from foreign intelligence in Operation Charly. Court judges were impeded from ruling against this initiative via Operation Silence, and MIR leaders Edgardo Enriquez and Jorge Fuentes were attacked in this initiative. DINA contributed greatly to this operation, which forced Martin Almada to listen to the torture of his wife over telephone. Archives of Terror in Asuncion recorded the actions of this initiative, which was spearheaded by Augusto Pinochet. For ten points, name this CIA-backed cleanup of political enemies and communists in South American countries.", "answer": "Operation<b> Condor</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "The ships Goeben and Breslau were able to find haven in this nation\u2019s waters. The Treaty of Erzincan helped end one conflict that this nation entered after the Battle of Odessa. This nation, which lost control of Jerusalem to Edmund Allenby, was led by the Pashas Enver and Talaat. The Treaties of Sevres and Lausanne brought an end to this empire. It faced a revolt in the Hejaz led by T.E. Lawrence and it perpetrated the Armenian Genocide. For ten points, name this empire that joined with the Central Powers in World War I, then dissolved after its defeat.", "answer": "<b> Ottoman</b> Empire", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This man promulgated the Wantage legal code. The battle of Maldon took place under this monarch, whose brother was killed by Queen Elfrida. Thorkell the Tall attacked this monarch\u2019s kingdom, and this monarch unwisely ordered the St. Brices Day Massacre. This monarch was the father of both Edward the Confessor and Edmund Ironsides. The Danegeld tributes were controversially paid by, for ten points, what monarch whose epithet actually means he was poorly advised?", "answer": "<b> Aethelred</b> the Unready (or<b> Aethelred II</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "One party formed for this election year was comprised of remnants of the earlier Opposition party. Two minor parties in this election included the People\u2019s Party and Liberty Party, the latter of which nominated Gerrit Smith. One party carried only Missouri in this year after it nominated the formulator of the Freeport Doctrine, and John Bell Hood\u2019s ticket carried only 3 states for the Constitutional Union Party. For ten points, name this presidential election year in which four parties split the electoral college, allowing the Republican Abraham Lincoln to take the White House.", "answer": "Election of<b> 1860</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>According to legend, one of these people successfully carried water in a sieve to prove her innocence. They were responsible for the preparation of mola salsa, a mixture of flour and salt, that was used in every official (+) sacrifice. According to Zosimus\u2019s</b><em><b> Historia Nova</b></em><b>, the last of these people cursed Stilicho\u2019s wife Serena for desecrating the temple of Rhea Silvia. These people took a vow of (*)</b> chastity for 30 years, that if broken, led to the violator being buried alive in the Campus Sceleratus. One of the chief duties of these people was to keep the sacred fire of the deity they served burning. For ten points, name these priestesses of the Roman goddess of the hearth.", "answer": "<b> Vestal Virgin</b>s", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>One work by the sculptor consists of a circular stone table ringed by twelve hourglass-shaped seats. That piece is part of an ensemble that also includes a tower consisting of</b> <b>seventeen-and-a-half stacked (+)</b> <b>rhomboids, built to commemorate World War I veterans</b> <b>at Targu Jiu. He also created an elongated bronze sculpture which was the subject of a (*) </b>court case after American customs officials initially refused to categorize it as art. For ten points, name this abstract Romanian sculptor of<em> Endless Column</em> and<em> Bird In Space</em>.", "answer": "Constantin<b> Br\u02c6ancusi</b> ([brin-koosh], but be lenient with phonetic pronunciations)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This leader\u2019s party rose to power after a series of protests against water privatization in the city of Cochabamba. Shortly after being inaugurated, this leader of the Movement for Socialism adopted a (+) \u201cCoca yes, Cocaine no!\u201d farming policy in opposition to American interests. In February 2016, this successor of Eduardo Rodriguez lost a referendum to extend his term limits to allow him to run again in 2020. In 2013, this leader\u2019s (*)</b> flight out of Moscow was grounded in Vienna after it was suspected that his plane contained Edward Snowden. For ten points, name this current President of Bolivia.", "answer": "Evo<b> Morales</b> Page 9", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>The Suka Wars were fought throughout these locations. During a 1953 incident, Janis Mendriks was killed when soldiers fired into a crowd at one of these institutions. Naftaly</b> <b>Frenkel established a system of (+)</b> <b>rations used at these locations. According to Anne</b> <b>Applebaum, two people who escaped one of these institutions invited a chef along with them so he could be used as food. The first one of these locations opened in 1921 on the (*)</b> Solovetsky Islands. The town of Vorkuta was created to support, for ten points, what Soviet prison camps?", "answer": "<b> gulag</b>s (accept<b> Soviet labor camps</b>; prompt on labor camp; prompt on prisons)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>After the passing of a law named for this region, governor Guy Carleton was accused of</b> <b>attempting to entrench Catholicism here. Richard Montgomery and (+)</b> <b>Benedict Arnold</b> <b>led a failed attempt to capture this region that prompted John Burgoyne\u2019s Hudson River campaign. In a 1759 battle in this region, both the (*)</b> Marquis de Montcalm and James Wolfe were killed. This region was captured by the British in the Seven Years War after a victory at the Plains of Abraham. For ten points, name this region, a modern day French-speaking Canadian province.", "answer": "<b> Quebec</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Charles Rose and John Bly were the only people executed for their roles in this event. James Bowdoin, who took over as Governor for the ill John Hancock, responded brutally to this event and promptly lost the next gubernatorial election to Hancock. (+) Samuel Adams briefly considered suspending</b><em><b> habeas corpus</b></em><b> during this event, in which the \u201cRegulators\u201dformed an (*)</b> anti-tax militia that shut down courts and tried to take the Springfield Armory. For ten points, name this 1786 rebellion of Massachusetts farmers that illustrated the weakness of the Articles of Confederation.", "answer": "<b> Shays\u2019</b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This man ended Quintus Sertorius\u2019 revolt, and it took this man just a few months to end a wave of piracy after he was given a navy by the Lex (+) Gabinia. This man won a minor victory at the Battle of Dyrrhachium, about a month before he was forced into fighting against the Populares in Greece. Those battles were fought as this man faced against a former (*) </b> ally, who had joined this man in an alliance with Marcus Licinius Crassus. For ten points, name this member of the First Triumvirate whose loss at Pharsalus allowed Julius Caesar to win the Roman Civil War.", "answer": "<b> Pompey</b> the Great (or Gnaeus<b> Pompei</b>us Magnus) Page 10", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}